Thomas Trevorrow

Human Resources Professional

Pardeeville, WI - Email me on Indeed: indeed.com/r/Thomas-Trevorrow/80e5ffe3ff274ed8

A civilian veteran of Operation Enduring Freedom in Afghanistan and Kuwait, highly motivated and customer driven professional, dedicated to providing extraordinary solutions to complex problems and is recognized for an uncompromising commitment to ethical, moral, and legal accountability. Mission and vision motivated to achieve organizational objectives, possesses the technical expertise to promote the strategic and tactical role of HR management while fostering teamwork between employees and management.

Willing to relocate: Anywhere

Authorized to work in the US for any employer

WORK EXPERIENCE

Human Resources Manager

Vectrus Systems Corporation - Colorado Springs, CO - January 2015 to May 2016

Manage 16 HR professionals providing support to over 700 US direct-hire employees. Responsible management of benefits administration, employee relations, policy development/review, management coaching and consultation, performance management, talent sourcing, compensation, data reporting, and a support services center.

- Manager and direct the Personnel Service Center (PSC) a support service center supporting 700 direct hire employees and over 1300 subcontract foreign national employees.
- Work with functional partners Legal, Finance, IT, and Department leadership across the program to ensure the aligned and effective delivery of HR support/services to the business and functions
- Help drive all people initiatives and practices including recruitment, talent, leadership development, performance management, organizational design, compensation, benefits, diversity, etc.
- Partner with department leadership and senior program management to establish and measure key people metrics that are aligned with project and company goals
- Working in harmony with Talent COE and program hiring managers, conduct organizational talent assessments, monitor staffing levels, continually drive improvements in talent development and acquisition
- Ensure employees and managers receive the appropriate counseling, guidance and support on employee relations issues
- Subject matter expert on applicable US labor laws and local labor regulations

Human Resources Supervisor SR. / Manager

Fluor, Inc - Greenville, SC - April 2010 to October 2014

Manage HR functional services within supported units including: staffing, employee relations, performance management, HR policy implementation, compensation & benefits administration, and related functions. Managed a team of six HR Generalists providing support to over 9,000 direct hire employees working in challenging and environmentally adverse conditions.

- Monitor performance of the project with leadership team and make adjustments to improve the overall efficiency and effectiveness of the team
- Spearhead programs and initiatives to drive staffing strategies, career development, and efficient mobility across the program
- Develop individual and organization capabilities through the deployment of performance measurement and assessment tools
- Subject matter expert on applicable US labor laws and local labor regulations

Human Resources Business Segment Manager

Kellogg Brown & Root - Houston, TX - July 2004 to April 2010

Multi-site manager of HR services to include training and development, policy administration, and staffing and recruitment. Develop and implement strategic business objectives within a start-up recruitment and training and development program for over 5,000 local hires. Establish the strategic objectives and implement process and procedures to meet company and client requirements. Monitor achievements and develop metrics reflecting the success of the program. Directed a team of 10 HR professionals located at seven different sites across Afghanistan. Provided HR support to departments and project management in an adverse and challenging environment.

- Provide opportunities for employees to acquire skilled trade, computer, clerical and administrative competencies
- Manage the delivery of information and details to direct hire employees concerning impending employment layoffs
- · Coordinate smooth and seamless transitions during contract and/or employment changeover
- · Identify cost saving measures for department
- Monitor performance of the department with leadership team; make adjustments to improve the overall efficiency and effectiveness of the team
- Subject matter expert on applicable US labor laws and local labor regulations

EDUCATION

Master of Business Administration in International Business

Liberty University - Lynchburg, VA 2008 to 2011

BBA in Human Resources

University of Wisconsin - Milwaukee, WI 1981 to 1991

SKILLS

HRIS (10+ years), Talent Acquisition (10+ years), Employee Relations (6 years), Human Resources (10+ years), Business Management (10+ years), Staffing (10+ years), Benefits Administration (5 years), Policy Development (8 years)

LINKS

https://www.linkedin.com/in/trevorrowthomas

CERTIFICATIONS/LICENSES

Professional in Human Resources (PHR)

January 2011 to January 2014 Pursuing SPHR in July, 2016

US Secret Clearance

May 2010 to May 2020

GROUPS

Society for Human Resource Management

Sigma Beta Delta Business Honor Society

ADDITIONAL INFORMATION

PROFICIENCIES

STRATEGIC HR PROJECT MANAGEMENT

- Managed the development and delivery of a nationwide internal staffing program, helped to reduce vacancies within critical job functions
- Led HRIS team in the development of a program-wide employee accountability system Supervised the development and implementation of customer feedback surveys improving customer service
- Led the development and implementation of a travel and expense accountability system, over 40,000 travel and expense transactions annually saving client approximately \$5 million during life of contract
- Conceptualizing and presenting external sourcing process to reduce the time to fill a vacancy from 14 weeks to 4

ORGANIZATIONAL DESIGN & DEVELOPMENT

- Manage performance evaluations and assessments
- Strength (staffing) management, internal recruitment, sourcing, on-boarding
- Developed an organizational structure for employees across 90 departments
- Designed training and development program for over 5,000 employees
- Developed compensation structure for 17 different job classifications

RISK MANAGEMENT AND MITIGATION

- Manage program-level employee relations to include investigations, consultations, mediations, and sensing sessions
- Reduced number of hotline calls and OMBUDs cases to lowest level in 5 years
- Set high level of integrity and expectations within HR and ER
- · Quick and efficient resolution of all investigations
- Advocate and practitioner of an open door policy for all employees

CHANGE MANAGEMENT

- Rewarded for seamless transition of 2500 personnel to new contractor
- Facilitated the smooth delivery of new employment agreements and offer letters for 700 employees during two "Bridge" contracts and two "Bridge" extension in less than 15 months
- Orchestrated the delivery of multiple reductions in force actions (layoffs) due to contract downsizing, and organizational restructuring
- Design, deliver, and offer coaching for routine HR policy and practice changes
- Organize and administer town hall meetings, all-hands functions, and sensing sessions allowing employees "open-mic" opportunities to voice questions and concerns

KAIZEN - DRIVING PROCESS IMPROVEMENT

- Designed the "Triple R Focus" Ready, Responsive, and Resilient
- o Full participation of department
- o Improve customer service focus
- Present broad scale process improvements to Senior Management

- o Streamlined talent sourcing
- o Employee tracking and accountability
- o Travel tracking and expense reporting
- o Internal application and recruiting process
- Review and editing of all work processes, instructions, project orders, and operating procedures on an annual basis, ISO 9001 standard

TECHNICAL

HRIS – Applicant Tracking (TALEO, Brass Ring) – SAP –MS Access – Excel WORD – Power Point – VISIO – Project – Live Cycle – Java Script – VBA – and more...